Guide to the Prize Essay Collection, 1872-2017
Prize Essay Collection, 1872-2017
- Series XVI Messenger-Chalmers Prize
  - Graduate award: Norman D. Roth; "The Development and Nature of Hebrew Secular Poetry in Muslim Spain (10th-12th Centuries).", 1975 (Box 21)
  - "Perspectives on Henry VIII and Cardinal Wolsey in the English Renaissance" by Frank V. Cespedes, 1977 (Box 21)
  - "An Analysis of Thomas Mann's Bekenntnisse Des Hochstaplers Felix Krull" by Daniel Sebastian Fredrich, 1978 (Box 21)
  - "The Transformation in Warfare During the Years 200-1000" by John D. Williams, 1978 (Box 21)
  - "Reluctant Royalists: Oxford Citizens and the English Civil War In Historical Context" by Cathy Herbert, 1984 (Box 21)
  - "Letters from the Diaspora" by Alexander Learned Singer, pseud. Hasdai ibn Shaprut (Box 21)
  - "'Hempire': Patriotism, Empire, and the British Working Class circa 1902," Gary M. Sernovitz, 1995 (Box missing)
- Series XVII. The Morrison Prize Poems
  - Helen of Heaven and Helen of Earth, by Clarence Earl Simonson, 1912 (Box 22)
  - A Mood, by Morris G. Bishop, 1913 (Box 22)
  - A Captive, and A Winter Talk, by Paul B. Schumm, 1914 (Box 22)
  - Sonnet, by Archibald Oboler, 1916 (Box 22)
  - The Baron's Daughter, by J. G. Schurman, Jr., 1916 (Box 22)
  - The Comet, The Beah-comber, Brushwood Fires, Pheidippides, Disillusionment, The Weed, by Samuel Wilson, 1917 (Box 22)
  - 1917, Peace, War, April 1917, "I went today", Wind! I am strong", "I am earth-bound", "Give not to me", "It was the silent, holy night", "The old wives rise", "I know a house", by Miss Edith Horton, 1918 (Box 22)
  - To a Dreamer, The Night-Shift, Coeur du Printemps, Night, The Alchemist, by DeElbert Keenan, 1919 (Box 22)
  - The Singer, Heart's Desire, Moods, Lullaby, The Dance of Death, by Frederick H. Lape, 1920a (Box 22)
  - Cathedrals of Old France, The Firefly, Villanelle, Silken Sails of Mystery, by L. E. Kittredge, 1920b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Dale Raymond Mitchell, 1921 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Robert Collyer Washburn, 1922a (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Mary G. Willcox, 1922b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Helen Martha Peavy and James Hutton, 1924a & b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Edith Horton, 1925a (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Elizabeth Rauschenbusch, 1925b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Hyman Yusewitz, 1926 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by William Bradford Willcox, 1928 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Miss Kimi Gengo, 1929a (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by James B. Gitlitz, 1929b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Miss Kimi Gengo, 1930a (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by James B. Gitlitz, 1930b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Julia Eaton, 1932a (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Muriel F. Hochdorf, 1932b (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by W. H. Sternberg, 1933 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Robert P. Darlington, George Eiten, Lucille V. Oaklander, 1948 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Robert Wheller and M. Irving Clifford, 1949 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Susan E. Goodman, 1954 (Box 22)
  - Fruit from Every Tree, by Sandra Montola, 1955 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Dorothy Gilbert, 1957 (Box 22)
  - Poems submitted by Roger Harry Fogelman, 1958 (Box 22)
- Series XVIII. The Sherman-Bennett Prize
  - Free Government by Harry Z. Harris, 1912 (Box 23)
  - Government and Administration, by Seth Victorius Elting, 1914 (Box 23)
  - The Reform Movement in American Politics, by W. D. Smith, 1916 (Box 23)
  - China and a Free Government, by Che Kwei Chen, 1919 (Box 23)
  - Municipal Government in the Hands of the People, by Lawrence B. June, 1920 (Box 23)
  - Immigration Regulation and the Principles of Free Government, by H. Solovay, 1921 (Box 23)
  - The Jury and Free Government, by Harold D. Feuerstein, 1929 (Box 23)
  - The Basis of Obedience, by W. H. Sternberg, 1933 (Box 23)
  - Constitutional Theory of Sir Edward Coke, by Francis D. Wormuth, 1934 (Box 23)
  - America, Democracy, and 1941, by Bruce Johnston, 1941 (Box 23)
  - The Principles of Free Government, by Harry Jindwich Benda, 1954 (Box 23)
  - Alien and Sedition Acts, 1957, by Stephen Alan Schuker, 1957 (Box 23)
- Series XIX. Sampson Fine Arts Competition
  - Modern Art and Peruvian Pottery: A Comparison and Discussion by Barbara Loebenstein, 1957 (Box missing)
- Series XX. The Woodford Prize, [all known competitors] (whole program is usually included; listed below are the indicated winners)
  - Burke and Webster as Orators, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Circumstances in the State of Society which Distinguish the Modern from the Ancient Orator, n.d. (Box 23)
  - The Medieval and Modern Ideal, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Public Opinion, the Standard of Criminal Punishment, by "Bishop Butler", n.d. (Box 23)
  - National Unity as a Tendency of the Age, by "Chie", 1872 (Box 23)
  - National Constitutions, a Growth and Development, by anon., 1873 (Box 23)
  - The Religion of Thomas Paine, by Arthur L. Andrews, 1893 (Box 23)
  - A Eulogy on John Bright, by E. I. White, 1893 (Box 23)
  - Lynch Law and Civilization, by Herbert L. Fordham, 1894 (Box 23)
  - Education and Ideal Citizenship, by George Dyer, 1895 (Box 23)
  - Truth and Dogma: The Irrepressible Conflict in Massachusets, by Charles Rammelkamp, 1896 (Box 23)
  - The Practical Age, by Daniel Wells, 1897 (Box 23)
  - The South and the Negro, by Charles Mayer, 1898 (Box 23)
  - The Attainable Ideal in Politics, by Herbert Lee, 1899 (Box 23)
  - The New Social Consciousness, by Eugene T. Lies, 1900 (Box 23)
  - Judaism - Its Mission in the Twentieth Century, by Sidney S. Lowenthal, 1901 (Box 24)
  - Liberty or Law: A Plea for Private Enterprise, by Michael Ford, 1902 (Box 24)
  - Southward, Ho!, by Alfred Huger, 1903 (Box 24)
  - The Debt of Humanity to the Engineer, by Harry F. Porter, 1905 (Box 24)
  - The Lawyer: Money Maker or Peace-Maker?, by G. G. Bogert, 1906 (Box 24)
  - The Power of the Individual, by N. D. Becker, 1906 (Box 24)
  - William Winthrop Taylor, 1907 (Box 24)
  - Elizabeth Ellsworth Cook, 1908 (Box 24)
  - The Price of Democracy, by A. Levine, 1909 (Box 24)
  - The World and the College, by Hymen Barr, 1910 (Box 24)
  - George Morris Wolfson, 1911 (Box 24)
  - Alan Husted Colcord, 1912 (Box 24)
  - Leslie Herbert Gloser, 1913 (Box 24)
  - Harold Riegelman, 1914 (Box 24)
  - Duane Spencer Hatch, 1915 (Box 24)
  - Morris Julius Escoll, 1916 (Box 24)
  - Ying Ching Yang, 1917 (Box 24)
  - The Lansing-Ishii Agreement, by Chen Ku, 1918 (Box 25)
  - Walter Measday, Jr., 1919 (Box 25)
  - Universal Military Service, by W. H. Farnham, 1920 (Box 25)
  - Irma Greenwalt, 1921 (Box 25)
  - Amnesty for Political Prisoners, by Madeline Grosshandler, 1922 (Box 25)
  - The Significance of Unemployment, by Esther Antell, 1923 (Box 25)
  - Louis Pasteur, by Sidney Goldstein, 1924 (Box 25)
  - Cultural Barrenness of American Life, by Katz, 1925 (Box 25)
  - The Scholar in the State, by M. H. Friedman, 1926 (Box 25)
  - An American Statesman, by Donald C. Bryant, 1927 (Box 25)
  - Patriotism - Sentiment of Sentimentality, by Robert D. Jones, 1928 (Box 26)
  - Shall We Let Man Live?, by Ida Blinkoff, 1929 (Box 26)
  - Armenia's Plea for Justice, by A. L. Abkarian, 1930 (Box 26)
  - Latin-America and Dollar Diplomacy, by Gerardo Auguste, 1931 (Box 26)
  - No Compromise With War, by Albert E. Arent, 1932 (Box 26)
  - A Requiem for the Civil Jury, by David Altman, 1933 (Box 26)
  - Peace Through Revolution, by Fred Berkowitz, 1934 (Box 26)
  - A New Future, by S. H. Bolz, 1935 (Box 26)
  - Christianity: A Philosophy of Action, by Fellows, 1936 (Box 27)
  - New Patriotism, by Clarke T. Case, 1938 (Box 27)
  - A Positive Peace Policy, by Leon Marsh, 1939 (Box 27)
  - Need We Fear for Democracy?, by Robert Hogsett, Jr., 1940 (Box 27)
  - Light in the Shadows, by Herbert Abrams, 1941 (Box 27)
  - no winner indicated, 1942 (Box 27)
  - no winner indicated, 1943 (Box 27)
- Series XXI. Unknown Prize
  - "Lincoln and Davis," by H. S. Thayer, pseudonym "Sergius", 1891 (Box 27)
  - "The Crisis of 1896, The Place of 'l'experience radicale' in French History" by Leslie Decker (L. E. Fraternite), n.d. (Box 27)
- Series XXII. Moses Coit Tyler Prize
  - "Dean Atcheson and the Ideological Origins of the Cold War" by George S. Lustig, 1978 (Box 28)
  - "Herman Melville's Typee: Preconception and Perception in Polynesia" by John Samson, 1979 (Box 28)
  - "The Exile of the Dead: New York's 1823 Interment Law. A Study in Cultural Conflict" by Eric Himmel, 1979 (Box 28)
  - "Bring us Together: Congressional Reaction to the Invasion of Cambodia, 1970" by Marie Gottschalk, 1980 (Box 28)
  - "Seabrook Action Drama: a Reading of an Anti-Nuclear Event" by William T. Vollmann, Arts '81, 1981 (Box 28)
- Series XXIII. Dorothy Sugarman Poetry Prize
  - John J. Whalen (A & S; '80), 1978 (Box 29)
  - Jon Tabakin (Honorable mention: Benjamin A. Liemer ), 1979 (Box 29)
  - Gail Tischkoff, David Laws, Becky Myers, 1980 (Box 29)
  - Howard S. L. Coale, 1981 (Box 29)
  - Timothy W. Muskat, Arts '82, 1982 (Box 29)
  - Gerard Nadeau, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Myra Koonce, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Thomas Hawks, 1990 (Box 29)
  - Matthew Zarnowiecki, 1997 (Box 29)
- Series XXIV. Elmer Markham Johnson Prize
  - Suzanne Eck, "The Isle of Avalon", 1978 (Box 29)
  - Alan G. Dexter, no title (English), Fall 1978 (Box 29)
  - Jennifer Park, "Taylor's Cosmological Argument for the Existence of God" (Philosophy), Fall 1978 (Box 29)
  - Susan Conrad, "Dylan Thomas' 'Fern Hill' " (English), Spring 1979 (Box 29)
  - Lynne Chase, "A Question of Understanding" (English), Fall 1979 (Box 29)
  - John Golder, "Troilus and Cressida: Contradictions of Love, War, and Moral Choice", Spring 1980 (Box 29)
  - Kenneth Locke, "The Western Quest: A Summing Up?" (Government 100.1), Fall 1980 (Box 29)
  - Geoffrey Potter, "Wealth Tradition Family", Spring 1981 (Box 29)
  - Cynthia Cupples, "The Horse Dealer's Daughter" and "The Magic Barrel", Fall 1981 (Box 29)
  - Michele Marie Stern, "Faulkner's Use of Verb Tense in As I Lay Dying" (English 270), Spring 1982 (Box 29)
  - Leigh Polk, "Artistic Indulgence" (English 108), Spring 1982 (Box 29)
  - Heidi Duitsman "The Barber of St. Petersburg" (Russian Literature 104), Fall 1982 (Box 29)
  - Mirian Reshotko, Gatsby: Simplicity Fails, (English 270.2) (2 copies), Spring 1983 (Box 29)
  - Roger Giner-Sorolla, "Mr. T" (Fr. Lit. 109), Fall 1984 (Box 29)
  - Nick Paige, "Techniques of 'Enduring Suspense'" (English 108), Spring 1985 (Box 29)
  - Ellen McGill, "The Bones of Djalming: Social Nasties and Political Questions" (Biology and Society 104), Spring 1986 (Box 29)
  - Eric Franz, "The English Game Laws" (Law Liberty and Crime in England, 1700-1850) [E. A. Reynolds], Spring 1986 (Box 29)
  - Elizabeth Briskin, "The Character of Joab", Fall 1987 (Box 29)
- Series XXV. Kasdan-Montessori Peace Prize Essay
  - Educational Reform and Peace by John D. Tower, Government 181, 1981-82 (Box 33)
  - If Humanity Can be Educated for Peace by Amy Kenton, Introduction to International Relations, 1982-83 (Box 33)
  - The Modern State: A View on War and the Social Contract by Alexander Jonas, Government 383, 1983-84 (Box 33)
  - Prisoner's Dilemma and The Analysis of International Conflict by Ngoh Hock-Soon, Government 477, 1984-85 (Box 33)
  - Morality in the Nuclear Age: Past, Present and Future by Ethan Oelman, Government 384, 1986-87 (Box 33)
  - The West German Peace Movement: Cyclical or Unique? by Aaron Karnell, Government 395, 1989 (Box 29)
- Series XXVI. Class of 1916 Prize (Best Senior Honors Essay)
  - "Strategies for revision in the novels of Margaret Drabble" (75 pp. Typescript) [1st prize], by Nancy GLazener, Spring 1983 (Box 31)
  - "Thomas Pynchon And The Language of Science" (28 pp. Typescript) [2nd prize], by Joseph Tabbi, Spring 1983 (Box 31)
- Series XXVII. The Douglas E. Whitney Prize
  - Intellectual Property Protection for Computer Software: A Discussion of How Legal Cases Have been Decided That Turn on Technical Points in the Face of Scientific Uncertainty and A Proposed Better Way for the Legal System to Provide This Needed Protection ( Edward N. Gewirtz ), 1988 (Box 28)
  - The International Transport of Hazardous Wastes ( Sharon B. Skolnik ), 1989 (Box 28)